Keith Marchant

10 Yeramba Cres, Berowra, NSW. 2081 kemarchant@outlook.com 0413 764 524

PROFILE

Software developer, architect, and manager with 14+ years' experience developing web and server applications for multiple industries. Currently focused on helping clients adopt cloudnative solutions while upskilling and growing development teams. Seeking opportunities to assist in the development of event-driven solutions that provide a first-class customer and development experience.

SKILLS

- 4 years' experience managing and mentoring a team of software developers
- 14 years' experience developing full-stack applications using C# and the .NET stack
- Experienced developing with Blazor, MVC, Web API, WCF, WPF, F#, Angular, PowerShell, SQL Server, MySQL, MongoDB, CosmosDB
- Designed, and delivered, event-driven serverless solutions in Azure
- Skilled in Git, TeamCity, GitHub Actions, Azure DevOps, Octopus Deploy, Docker, Kubernetes, Bicep
- Involved in the delivery and management of software projects for multi-country teams
- Experienced in migrating to, and using, the AWS cloud environment
- Strong verbal and written communication skills
- Reliable goal oriented individual with strong work ethic

EXPERIENCE

Azenix Lead Software Engineer Sept 2022 – June 2023 Azenix is a .NET & Azure consulting organisation existing as one of the brands offered by the Mantel Group

- Managed project governance and client stakeholders through multiple engagements
- Designed and built event-sourced systems backed by CosmosDB & Azure Functions
- Delivered Azure Accelerate workshops
- Integrated multiple internal & third-party systems into an event-driven architecture to address key compliance requirements for clients

InfoTrack Pty Ltd Solution Architect Jan 2021 – Aug 2022 InfoTrack provides a single platform for E-Conveyancing, due diligence, and more; tightly integrated into multiple practice management software solutions.

- Implemented the vision of a shared software platform across three countries
- Responsible for the migration of authentication to IdentityServer 4 & OIDC
- Produced and delivered strategy and training material for worldwide developers
- Architected the replacement of the legacy .NET 4.5 ordering system with a collection of .NET Core microservices and NuGet clients
- Introduced DataDog APM and infrastructure monitoring to track performance and triage issues within the new ordering system

 Transitioned applications from IIS and Rancher hosting to an infrastructure-as-code Kubernetes pipeline

InfoTrack Pty Ltd

Development Manager

May 2016 - Dec 2020

- Managed and mentored multiple developers
- Migrated hosting from private cloud to AWS and assisted with the adoption of AWS managed services
- Managed the replacement of synchronous systems with an event driven architecture backed by MassTransit and AmazonMQ

InfoTrack Pty Ltd

.Net Developer

Sep 2015 - Apr 2016

- Released new corporate product offerings integrated with ASIC written in Knockout JS and ASP.NET MVC
- Implemented MongoDB document storage for existing XML archives
- Implemented new CI/CD processes and infrastructure worldwide using TeamCity and Octopus Deploy

BlueSun Inc. **Senior Software Developer** May 2010 – Aug 2015 BlueSun is a small Canadian company that specialises in providing web software for the life insurance and mutual fund industries via their WealthServ products.

- Developed new products using C#, Java, JavaScript, MVC, & SQL Server
- Managed the WealthServ Insurance product as the lead developer
- Triaged all issues related to the WealthServ Insurance platform
- Converted client data for new client installations
- Supported the sales process for prospective clients

Electronic Arts Canada Associate Software Engineer May 2009 – Aug 2009 EA Canada is responsible for the development of multiple major sports video game franchises released yearly.

- Employed as part of a work placement through the University of Waterloo
- Assisted in the development of FIFA 10 on Xbox 360 & PS3
- Implemented tool support code in C# and C++/CLI

EDUCATION

University of Waterloo Bachelor of Computer Science with Honours Co-op program & Business Option

Sep 2005 – Apr 2010

INTERESTS

- Avid soccer player
- Technology enthusiast
- Runner and cyclist

REFERENCES

Available upon request